# **Eliot Piering**

## Software Developer

eliot@eliotpiering.com (617) 943-5514

### **Profile**

Experienced full-stack developer specializing in Ruby and JavaScript. Versatile, practical, and a good teammate. I take pride in writing quality readable code, using the right tools for the job, and developing solutions for the end user first.

### **Skills**

- Languages
   Ruby, JavaScript, Elixir, Elm
- Frameworks
   Rails, Ember, Phoenix
- Other Skills and Tools Linux, AWS, Git, MySQL

### **Experience**

#### Knowlnk

Software Developer

October 2017 - October 2019

- Lead Developer of ePulse, a Ruby on Rails app that serves as Knowlnk's control center for managing elections.
- Wrote and designed API's for our iOS app that poll workers used during elections and early voting periods. The api handled capturing voter check-ins, creating and updating voter registrations, canceling check-ins, sending and capturing signatures, printing ballots, spoiling ballots, and various other state specific election tasks.
- Developed a reactive user interface using Rails, JavaScript and CSS that enabled election officials to import, view and manage their voter data, election day inventory, and address any issues arising during early voting or on election day.
- Implemented robust reporting capabilities using lots of ActiveRecord and raw SQL that clients used to view vital data check points pre and post election.
- Integrated with a wide collection of third party Voter Registration systems.
- Engaged closely with clients to plan work and offer creative solutions for achieving any desired election day flows.

#### LaunchCode

Software Developer

April 2015 - May 2017

- Contributed to LaunchCode's core Ruby on Rails web application that enabled LaunchCode to evaluate potential candidates for apprenticeship programs, enroll students in education programs, and provides tailored administrator interface to manage users throughout the enrollment process.
- Tech lead on internal platform built using JavaScript and Ember that allows business development team to cultivate contacts with companies, search for qualified candidates, match candidates with open jobs, and track progress throughout the apprenticeship.
- Created, automated and maintained LaunchCode's infrastructure that powers various business tools and education systems. Utilized Amazon Web Services, shell scripts, and monitoring tools to provide consistent, stable and safely modifiable infrastructure.
- Collaborated on the creation of internal agile processes, instituting regular feedback loops, project planning/estimating, and code reviews ensuring high quality code that provides effective business solutions.

#### Radialogica

Software Developer

#### October 2013 - April 2015

- Built web software using Ruby on Rails and JavaScript with Ember that enabled secure file sharing and organization management.
- Developed cloud infrastructure using Docker and CoreOS, ensuring scalability, automation, security, while remaining HIPPA compliant.
- Mentored and onboarded new team members into the web project enabling them to make meaningful contributions shortly after joining the team.

### **Education**

Washington University in St. Louis June 2012 - May 2016

- B.S. in Psychology and Economics
- Graduated Magma Cum Laude in Psychology

### **Interests**

- Work on various programming side project for fun and learning. Currently I'm building a "sonos clone" using Elixir.
- Play the drums and piano and love to play in casual bands.

Eliot Piering — eliot@eliotpiering.com — (617) 943-5514